Finding Aid for the Music Calendar Collection, 1968-2007
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Music Calendar Collection, 1968-2007
Mus. Arc. 28
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
11 boxes 149 items
A collection of calendars with music-themed artwork and text, mostly published in the United States and Germany.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Music calendars acquired intermittently by the Music Library.
Accruals and Additions
Further accruals are possible.
Scope and Content Note
Most of the calendars in the collection feature reproductions of art and photographs that depict musical scenes, composers, performers, or instruments. Among the more well-represented topics in the collection are musical instruments, opera, jazz, and music manuscripts. Many calendars also include historical or biographical information, significant dates in musical history, and biographical or historical information about the creators of the artwork. In addition to reproductions of photographs and paintings, media represented include musical instruments, realia, sheet-music and album covers, and illuminated manuscripts and miniatures.
Historical Note
The Music Library staff created this collection by a variety of means: solicitation, collation of calendars received with existng serial subscriptions, and donation of calendars from personal sources.
Arrangement
The collection is one series, arranged by size, then grouped by publisher and arranged chronologically.
Container List
- Calendars, 1968-2007, I.
  - Kontrapunkt: Musik Kalender 1989 Furore, 11 x 15 cm.; monthly (Box 01, Item CAL001)
  - Fur Musikfreunde 1983 Ackermanns Kunstverlag, 25 x 17 cm.; monthly (Box 01, Item CAL002)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild Engagement Calendar: Giuseppe Verdi, His Life and Works in Pictures 1974 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 18 x 19 cm.; weekly (Box 01, Item CAL003)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild Engagement Calendar 1972 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 22 x 15 cm.; weekly (Box 01, Item CAL004)
  - Opera Stars 1982 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 24 x 19 cm.; weekly (Box 01, Item CAL005)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild Engagement Calendar: Donizetti 1979 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 24 x 19 cm.; weekly (Box 01, Item CAL006)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild Engagement Calendar: Mozart 1978 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 24 x 19 cm.; weekly (Box 01, Item CAL007)
  - Christophe Landon Rare Violins 2006 Christophe Landon, 18 x 18 cm.; monthly (Box 01, Item CAL008)
  - Early Music Vancouver: Vancouver Early Music Festival 2005 & Early Music Vancouver 2005-06 Season 2005 Early Music Vancouver, 22 x 21 cm.; monthly (Box 01, Item CAL009)
  - Guitar Player Presents: First Act Guitars 2006 First Act, 18 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 01, Item CAL010)
  - Music Calendar 1969 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL011)
  - Music Calendar 1970 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL012)
  - Music Calendar 1973 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL013)
  - Music Calendar 1976 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL014)
  - Music Calendar 1977 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL015)
  - Music Calendar 1978 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL016)
  - Music Calendar 1979 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL017)
  - Music Calendar 1980 C. F. Peters, 26 x 18 cm.; biweekly (Box 02, Item CAL018)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild Engagement Calendar 1971 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 15 x 21 cm.; weekly (Box 03, Item CAL019)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild Engagement Calendar 1973 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 18 x 19 cm.; weekly (Box 03, Item CAL020)
  - Metropolitan Opera Guild Engagement Calendar 1975 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 18 x 19 cm.; weekly (Box 03, Item CAL021)
  - Fur Musikfreunde: Ackermann Einsteckkalender fur 12 Postkarten 1987 Ackermanns Kunstverlag, 25 x 20 cm.; monthly (Box 03, Item CAL022)
  - Fur Musikfreunde: Ackermann Einsteckkalender 1984 Ackermanns Kunstverlag, 25 x 20 cm.; monthly (Box 03, Item CAL023)
  - Fur Musikfreunde: Ackermann Einsteckkalender fur 12 Postkarten 1989 Ackermanns Kunstverlag, 25 x 20 cm.; monthly (Box 03, Item CAL024)
  - Art of Sheet Music 1996 Calendar 1996 Elliott & Clark, 31 x 24 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL025)
  - Steinway: Family and Factory 1986 LaGuardia Community College, 23 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL026)
  - D'Addario 1994 Players Calendar 1994 D'Addario, 22 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL027)
  - Dr. Jazz Calendar: Bop Issue 1983 Jazz and Blues Centre, 24 x 29 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL028)
  - Music 1998 Prentice Hall, 22 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL029)
  - Musical Album 1980 Sandals Unlimited Designs, 22 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL030)
  - Musical Album 1981 Sandals Unlimited Designs, 22 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL031)
  - Musical Album 1983 Sandals Unlimited Designs, 22 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL032)
  - International Society of Bassists Portrait Calendar 2005 International Society of Bassists, 22 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL033)
  - Country Music History Calendar 1982 Country Music Foundation, 22 x 19 cm.; monthly (Box 04, Item CAL034)
  - Musica 1968: Ein Kunstkalender fur Musikfreunde 1968 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 05, Item CAL035)
  - Musica 1969: Ein Kunstkalender fur Musikfreunde 1969 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 05, Item CAL036)
  - Musica 1970: Ein Kunstkalender fur Musikfreunde 1970 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 05, Item CAL037)
  - Musica 1971: Ein Kunstkalender fur Musikfreunde 1971 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 05, Item CAL038)
  - Musica 1972: Ein Kunstkalender fur Musikfreunde 1972 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 05, Item CAL039)
  - Organa Europae 1971 Imprimeries Loos, 38 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL040)
  - Organa Europae 1979 Imprimeries Loos, 38 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL041)
  - Great Composer Calendar 1977 Bellerophon Books, 28 x 36 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL042)
  - Great Composer Calendar 1983 Bellerophon Books, 28 x 36 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL043)
  - Great Composer Calendar 1984 Bellerophon Books, 28 x 36 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL044)
  - Great Composer Calendar 1988 Bellerophon Books, 28 x 36 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL045)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1981 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL046)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1982 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL047)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1983 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL048)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1984 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL049)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1985 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL050)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1986 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL051)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1987 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL052)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1988 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL053)
  - Compleat Jazz Calendar 1989 Vince Danca, 29 x 26 cm.; monthly (Box 05, Item CAL054)
  - Musica 1974 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL055)
  - Musica 1975 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL056)
  - Musica 1977 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL057)
  - Musica 1978 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL058)
  - Musica 1979 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL059)
  - Musica 1980 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL060)
  - Musica 1981 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL061)
  - Musica 1982 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL062)
  - Musica 1983 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL063)
  - Musica 1984 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL064)
  - Musica 1985 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL065)
  - Musica 1986 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL066)
  - Musica 1988 Barenreiter, 27 x 29 cm.; biweekly (Box 06, Item CAL067)
  - Jose Carreras 1993 Verlag A. Barylli, 35 x 24 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL068)
  - Musikbilder auf Postkarten Calendarium 1989 Moeck, 35 x 25 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL069)
  - Calendarium 1979 Moeck, 34 x 30 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL070)
  - Official 1983 Country Calendar 1983 Country Music Foundation, 28 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL071)
  - Opera 1983 Tide Mark, 28 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL072)
  - Opera 1985 Tide Mark, 28 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL073)
  - Opera 1986 Tide Mark, 28 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL074)
  - Opera 1987 Tide Mark, 28 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL075)
  - Opera 1988 Tide Mark, 28 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL076)
  - Opera 1989 Tide Mark, 28 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL077)
  - Opera 1993 Tide Mark, 28 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL078)
  - Eastman: Reflections 1997 Eastman School of Music, 28 x 36 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL079)
  - Official 1984 Country Calendar 1984 Country Music Foundation, 28 x 36 cm.; monthly (Box 07, Item CAL080)
  - 1992 Classical Music Lovers' Calendar 1992 Pomegranate, 37 x 41 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL081)
  - Classical Music 1993 Pomegranate, 37 x 41 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL082)
  - Classical Music 1994 Pomegranate, 37 x 41 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL083)
  - Internationaler Opernkalender 1994 Verlag A. Barylli, 35 x 45 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL084)
  - Internationaler Opernkalender 1996 Verlag A. Barylli, 35 x 45 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL085)
  - Strad: The Amati Influence 1993 Strad, 43 x 30 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL086)
  - Strad: The Venetian School 1994 Strad, 43 x 30 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL087)
  - Early Music Calendar 1993 Musical Times, 32 x 43 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL088)
  - Wiener Opernkalender 1993 Verlag A. Barylli, 35 x 45 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL089)
  - Jazz '83 1983 Engelhardt & Bauer, 48 x 33 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL090)
  - Komponisten Kalendar 1994 Moeck, 49 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL091)
  - Tibia-Calendarium 1983 Moeck, 38 x 38 cm.; monthly (Box 08, Item CAL092)
  - Klingende Jahr 1978 Breitkopf & Hartel, 38 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL093)
  - Klingende Jahr 1980 Breitkopf & Hartel, 38 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL094)
  - Calendarium 1980 Moeck, 42 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL095)
  - Tibia-Calendarium 1982 Moeck, 42 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL096)
  - Tibia-Calendarium 1984: Holzblasinstrumente auf Bildern des 17. und 18. Jahrhunderts 1984 Moeck, 40 x 27 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL097)
  - Tibia-Calendarium 1985 Moeck, 40 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL098)
  - Musiker in "Kaiser Maximilian des Ersten diss namens hochloblichister gedechtnus Triumph" 1986 Moeck, 40 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL099)
  - Zeugnisse alter Musik 1970 Wolfgang Schwarze, 40 x 30 cm.; biweekly (Box 09, Item CAL100)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 1991 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL101)
  - Medieval and Renaissance Book Illumination 1992 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL102)
  - Medieval and Renaissance Book Illumination 1993 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL103)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 1994 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL104)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 1995 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL105)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 1996 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL106)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 1997 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL107)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 1998 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL108)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 2005 Muller und Schindler, 49 x 33 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL109)
  - Great Composers 1990 Calendar 1990 Bellerophon Books, 44 x 29 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL110)
  - Kompomistinnen 1987 Furore, 43 x 30 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL111)
  - Musik im Grunen 1989 Barenreiter, 43 x 30 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL112)
  - Minnesanger aus der Heidelberger Liederhandschrift Medieval Minstrels 1986 Dr. Rudolf Georgi, 48 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL113)
  - Minnesanger aus der Heidelberger Liederhandschrift Medieval Minstrels 1988 Dr. Rudolf Georgi, 48 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL114)
  - Minnesanger aus der Heidelberger Liederhandschrift Medieval Minstrels 1990 Dr. Rudolf Georgi, 48 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 09, Item CAL115)
  - Blue Note Jazz: The 60th Anniversary 1999 Calendar 1999 Avalanche, 31 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL116)
  - Blue Note Years: The Jazz Photography of Francis Wolff 1999 Universe, 31 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL117)
  - Magic of the Met: 1986 Metropolitan Opera Calendar 1986 Metropolitan Opera Guild, 31 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL118)
  - Musical Magic 1993 CEDCO, 31 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL119)
  - Official 1986 Country Calendar 1986 Country Music Foundation, 32 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL120)
  - Official 1987 Country Calendar 1987 Country Music Foundation, 32 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL121)
  - Official Country Calendar 1989 Country Music Foundation, 32 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL122)
  - Classical Music 1996 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL123)
  - Classical Music 1997 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL124)
  - Classic Jazz Calendar 1984 Pomegranate, 35 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL125)
  - Classic Jazz 1988 Pomegranate, 34 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL126)
  - Classic Jazz 1991 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL127)
  - Classic Jazz 1993 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL128)
  - Classic Jazz 1994 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL129)
  - Classic Jazz 1996 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL130)
  - Classic Jazz 1999 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL131)
  - Blues 1992 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL132)
  - Blues 1993 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL133)
  - Blues 1994 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL134)
  - Blues 1996 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL135)
  - Blues 1997 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL136)
  - Metropolitan Opera Presents 1991 Pomegranate, 31 x 34 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL137)
  - Metropolitan Opera 1993 Rizzoli, 33 x 33 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL138)
  - Zeugnisse alter Musik IX 1978 Wolfgang Schwarze, 35 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL139)
  - Zeugnisse alter Musik X 1979 Wolfgang Schwarze, 35 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL140)
  - Zeugnisse alter Musik XII 1981 Wolfgang Schwarze, 35 x 32 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL141)
  - Zeugnisse alter Musik XIII 1982 Wolfgang Schwarze, 32 x 35 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL142)
  - Jazz & Rock '75 1975 te Neues KG, 43 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL143)
  - Early Music Vancouver: Vancouver Early Music Festival 2006 & Early Music Vancouver 2006-07 Season 2006 Early Music Vancouver, 22 x 21 cm.; monthly (Box 10, Item CAL144)
  - Teatro alla Scala 1992 Ricordi, 56 x 43 cm.; monthly (Box 11, Item CAL145)
  - Christophe Landon Rare Violins 2007 Christophe Landon, 31 x 31 cm.; monthly (Box 11, Item CAL146)
  - Guild of American Luthiers 2007 Guild of American Luthiers, 48 x 28 cm.; yearly (Box 11, Item CAL147)
  - Medieval Book Illumination 2007 Muller und Schindler, 46 x 28 cm.; monthly (Box 11, Item CAL148)
  - Out to Lunch, Dedicated to Eric Dolphy, 1928-1964: A Celebration of Jazz 1991 Oscar Schneider Design, 69 x 45 cm.; monthly (Box 11, Item CAL149)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Calendars; Music calendars; Music in art; Musical instruments; Musicians
Genres
Calendars
Associated Material
Related Resources
Music Calendars Database searchable online.